GREGORY LAWRENCE



greglawrence.dev



bluhurr@gmail.com



781.470.0080



Waltham, MA

ABOUT ME

I have always been inspired and motivated by learning new and interesting skills, and am always finding new ways to apply those skills with fun and creativity. I especially enjoy front-end web development, especially working with 3D tools such as Three.js & React Three Fiber, alongside either HTML, CSS, and JavaScript, or using React and TailwindCSS to create unique and engaging web experiences.

EDUCATION

University of Massachusetts Lowell | 2016 - 2020

BS in Computer Science | Minor in Business | GPA: 3.420 | Cum Laude

Skills

Main Proficiencies

Web: JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Three.js, React Three Fiber, 8th Wall, WordPress

Game Development: PlayCanvas, Unity, Blender

Data Science: Python, Pandas, NumPy

Tools: Vim, Linux Terminal, Git, IntelliJ, WSL2

Familiarities (Technologies worked with in the past or more recently)

Web: React.js, Next.js, Gatsby, TailwindCSS, Material UI, SASS, Google Maps API, Docker

General Languages: C++, C#, C, Java, SQL

Miscellaneous

Office: Excel. Word. PowerPoint

Graphic/Video Design: Photoshop, Illustrator, InDesign, Gimp, Inkscape, DaVinci Resolve,

Premiere

Projects & Achievements

2023: Re-designed and developed my online portfolio website, using hand coded HTML, CSS, and JavaScript, alongside Three.js for the addition of engaging 3D elements.

2020: Led development of a road trip planning web app, "Tripster", as a college final project.

2015: Eagle Scout Boy Scouts of America

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

Planning Diva | Contracting as Software Engineer, 3D Animations | Remote | Apr. 2023 - Present

- Developing online 3D event planning tool using React Three Fiber, as part of overall SaaS event planning product.
- Guiding feature decisions for 3D planning tool and other 3D web related questions.

Mobilize Solutions | Web AR / Frontend Consultant | Remote | Nov. 2022 - Present

- Developing web based AR experiences using the 8th Wall platform and ensuring compatibility with their current mobile camera app.
- Helping inform AR & frontend related questions and needs.

VDA inc. | Contracting as Associate Designer / Technology Specialist | Remote | Oct. 2020 - Present

- Researching and implementing technologies such as PlayCanvas and Three.js to expand the company's virtual event offerings.
- Helping pioneer a brand new online 3D virtual web event experiences with other web developers and graphic design team.
- Aiding in graphic development, organization, and pricing of event booth prints and graphical elements.